

**APPLIED SCIENTIST II** 

#### **Details**

+1 (732) 853-9608 sborar12@gmail.com

#### Skills

#### Soft skills

Teamwork, Leadership, Communication

### **Programming languages**

Python (4 years)
Java (1 years)

#### **Frameworks and Libraries**

PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras Scikit Learn, Pandas, NumPy PySpark

#### **ML Project domains**

**Causal Inference** 

**Reinforcement learning** 

**Recommender systems** 

**Computer Vision** 

**Natural Language Processing** 

#### **Database**

MySql, BigQuery, Excel

#### **Tools**

Tableau, Jenkins (CI/CD)
Git, AWS, GCP (Cloud)

#### Languages

**English** 

Hindi

#### Miscellaneous

Experimentation, Hypothesis testing, A/B testing, Causal inference

#### **Profile**

Passionate Applied Scientist with 5 years of corporate experience + Dual degree Masters in Data Science and Artificial Intelligence with Honors. Experienced in researching state-of-the-art machine learning methods. Skilled in communicating complex ML concepts to business stakeholders. Publications in ECIR and IUI. Certified AWS Solutions Architect. WiDS (Women in Data Science) Ambassador 2024.

#### **Employment History**

# Applied Scientist II at Amazon Prime Video (Commerce optimization), London DECEMBER 2022 — JANUARY 2024

- Increased prime video rentals by 4.87% in North America by analyzing experimental data and identifying customer segments to personalize the position of offers –
  - Designed a strategy for unbiased data collection by exposing a customer segment to randomized offer positions and evaluated impact by generating synthetic data and inverse propensity weighting.
  - Created a dataset to build a click model by addressing disconnected input and output. Connected multiple data sources to get aggregate features like customer purchasing power and title popularity.
  - Performed drivers analysis using a click model. Used EDA, permutation
    importance, and model explainability to reliably identify the drivers of a
    click. Used the drivers to identify customers who have a higher probability
    to rent.

## Machine Learning Engineer at JP Morgan Chase (Finance), Hong Kong SEPTEMBER 2018 — AUGUST 2020

- Elevated the digital sales and marketing team's strategy by -
  - Predicting with 81.63% F1 score which funds are likely to be sold heavily next month using ensemble models.
  - Led the effort for an AI chat application using NLP libraries like spacy to help facilitate networking at a sales conference.
- Responsible for the growth and development of 2 interns.

#### **Publications**

# <u>Improving Recommender System Diversity with Variational Autoencoders</u> FEBRUARY 2022 — SEPTEMBER 2022

 Improved aggregate diversity of recommender systems in eCommerce by 29.71% by creating richer user representations using variational auto-encoders. This resulted in relevant yet diverse recommendations for millions of users.

### **Robust and Deployable Gesture Recognition for Smartwatches**

JUNE 2021 — AUGUST 2021

• Researched the impact of loss functions in an image classification task for improving robustness in smartwatch gesture recognition.

#### Education

### MS in Data Science, TU/e (Netherlands) and Aalto University (Finland)

SEPTEMBER 2020 — SEPTEMBER 2022

- EIT Digital Master School Scholarship 2020-2022
- Selected courses: Deep Learning, Methods of Data Mining, Machine Learning:
   Supervised, Complex Networks, Reinforcement learning

BEng in Computer Science, HKUST (Hong Kong)